So, I've been testing Xiaomi's nextG
flagship phone, and you know, sometimes
one phone company will copy another one,
but change it up a little bit. Well,
I've never seen a company change less
than Xiaomi has here. They've adjusted
the numbering on their phones to call
them the 17s. They've shifted their
naming structure to Pro and Pro Max.
They've announced the phones a month
early in September, all while featuring
a very familiar-looking camera plateau
design. Now, clearly, this is a
marketing trick. This is all to make
absolute sure that when you think about
the iPhone 17 Pros that you also think
and [music] maybe even come across
Xiaomi. And part of me thinks this is
really not a good look that this kind of
cheapens a brand that is otherwise
clearly capable of making [music] unique
tech of their own. But then part of me
completely gets here because when you
actually take the bait and you put these
phones side by side, it draws attention
to the really unique things that Xiaomi
is doing that no one [music] else is.
Like, oh yeah, did I mention Xiaomi's
camera plateau is also a full-on second
display. So, if you bought a 17 Pro,
this is what you'd get
a super tall box with a charger, a 100 W
charger casually in the box, the USBC
cable, and a little insert which has the
case, a lightly frosted hard shell.
That's a pretty high tier package.
And then this is the Pro Max, which has
all the same stuff inside.
So, the weird thing about this phone is
it looks almost intentionally like a
knockoff iPhone, right, with the naming
and the design. And to be fair, even the
user interface, like the home screen's
got Apple style icons. You pull down
from here, you've got Apple's control
center. I'm pretty sure I've even seen
some iOS 26 Liquid Glass inside of here.
I give him a year before they tell us
their CEO is now also called Tim. But
the thing is, it doesn't feel like a
knockoff. The display is bright and
super high-end. The borders around it
are every bit as thin and even as other
top phones. Every time you press things
and click buttons, the haptics are
phenomenal. Very satisfying experience
to type and navigate. Or let's just try
something for a second. This Pro over
here is a pretty tiny phone, right? It's
got triple cameras on the back. It's got
not one but two [music] displays. How
big of a battery do you think they've
managed to fit into here? 6,300
mAh. That's a 25% bigger battery than
the iPhone 17 Pro Max and [music] even
the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra. And so the
Xiaomi 17 Pro Max, 7,500,
50% bigger than those other phones. And
it translates, it is giving me stupid
levels of endurance. I feel like I'm a
kid again and I go into the candy store
and my mom hands me $50 to spend. You
could buy everything. And because it's
achieved using a silicon carbon battery
with the highest concentration of
silicon so far, it's not made the phone
any thicker or heavier. In fact, when
you pick it up, the first thing you
notice is that it's actually lighter
than the iPhone 17 Pro Max. Okay, fine.
But they have had to compromise on the
performance to get to this.
Psyche. These phones have 16 gigs of the
fastest RAM I've ever seen on a phone.
They've got the fastest storage and
they're basically the first phones to
have the new Snapdragon Elite Gen 5,
which is the chip that will power most
Android flagships next year. I tried a
whole load of tests and benchmarks on
it. And while I wouldn't call it a
transformational leap, it is firmly
ahead of this year's crop of Androids
like Samsung's S25 Ultra. It can get
quite hot on the sides, but not once
have I noticed that actually affecting
sustained performance. So, at least it
is effectively getting heat away from
the chip. So, it's pretty clear the
phone's fundamentals are crazy good. But
that's what makes this magic back screen
all the more interesting. Cuz [music]
clearly Xiaomi didn't need to do this.
The Xiaomi 17 Pro and Pro Max are not
one-off gimmick phones. They're not part
of a subbrand. They're not niche concept
devices that are only going to be
released as a test. These are Xiaomi's
mainline 2025 2026 flagship phones that
they will most likely release in all
their regions, which makes them like the
one launch that they wouldn't want to be
adding a potentially expensive to
produce potentially gimmicky toy to. And
so the fact that they've decided to go
for something so unconventional makes me
think one of two things that Xiaomi are
either a using this as a very expensive
piece of marketing, something to get
people talking and go viral on Tik Tok
because they know that once someone
considers their phone, they will become
impressed by all the other things that
it does. Or B that they are actually
confident that the second screen is the
future of the smartphone and that it's
going to stick around for good. So which
is it? Well, let's be very clear about
one thing right off the bat. We have
seen rear screens before. You've never
seen them like this because this rear
screen has the exact same display
characteristics as the front screen.
It's got the same 3000s of brightness,
the same 1 to 120 Hz refresh rate, the
same touch responsiveness, the same
cover glass. It doesn't feel tacked on.
And the fact that Xiaomi has heroically
pre-applied a screen protector to not
just the front screen, but also the back
screen has meant that I have not once
worried about putting it down on a
surface like this. But as beautiful as
it may be, no one's catching up with the
latest Mr. Who's the Boss videos on the
3 in between the cameras. So, what can
you do with this that you would actually
want to do with this? And this bar over
here can summarize how convinced or
unconvinced I am by the thing as we go.
So, level one, I guess, is
personalization. Xiaomi were telling me
that a big part of the appeal of this
phone will be the ability to express
yourself like never before. And I wasn't
ready for how hard they went with this.
So, you've got a whole load of different
clock faces. And this is already pretty
cool. You've got really intricate
mechanical ones. You've got simple ones
that you can recolor yourselves. And
then even this one with a step counter
built in. So, pretty similar to a
smartwatch [music] homepage. And
speaking of smart watches, this stretch
face feels like it is literally taken
straight from Apple's source code.
You've got pets that kind of interact as
you touch them. Decorate with a spunky
little sheep. Pretty sure that ain't a
sheep pel. But these are also really
high- res and surprisingly not that
tacky. Like one of them is this really
awesome butterfly cart that can actually
swim behind, in front of, [music] and
even through the current time. And then
if you don't like any of those, you can
build your own. You can choose whether
you want a clock or just text. You can
write whatever text you want and change
the color, the font size, the thickness.
But then with the background, it's not
just a pre-selected gallery. You can
also generate [music] with AI. And I've
never seen it done like this. This lets
you turn any image into a realistically
animated video customdesigned for this
rear [music] screen in any one of these
styles. I have fed this thing all sorts
of absolutely terrible photos of things,
but each time it comes back with
something that is shockingly usable.
From my favorite little plant that I
turned into a plushy to a selfie that
turned me into an anime villain. This is
such an excessively extra piece of
software. But I think that's exactly
what this needs cuz it's such an
excessively extra piece of hardware that
you need to justify it. So, so far I'm
impressed, but far from convinced cuz
whatever you set on this display, it's
going [music] to spend 99% of its time
dim like this. And then it's only when
you tap it that you wake it up.
Thankfully, it does do more than this
cuz then you can swipe down and you got
a music player, which honestly I think
looks stunning. And I can see the use
case of it. You got some friends over,
you're playing music, you want to
control it, but you don't actually want
to be on your phone. You can pin things.
So, let's say you needed to remember to
buy milk, you can [music] pin the note
for that or a photo of milk if that's
how you roll. They have made it pretty
convenient cuz you can even just circle
things and the phone will extract the
text from that thing and create this
permanent note. It's like [music] the
2025 equivalent of writing something on
your hand. Trying to think of all the
things you could do with this. I guess
you could pin a QR code that you want
people to scan or if you've just started
a business using it as free advertising
as like a tiny little billboard. It
feels like every company now has added
some sort of second space to their phone
software to give you small updates like
dynamic island on the iPhone or the now
bar on Samsung. And clearly Xiaomi are
trying to make the second screen their
version of this. So they [music] want
this to work with all the meal delivery
apps and the flight tracker apps. But
right now that's all quite limited cuz
it's not launched globally yet. So the
only thing I have now for app
integration is if you set a timer in
your clock then the back of your phone
can carry that timer on with this liquid
actually depleting along with your time.
It's actually kind of stressing me out.
There is also a notifications [music]
aspect, too, which I guess a very
similar concept to nothing phones where
when you're out at dinner, you can stick
your phone down so that you're present,
but knowing that if someone calls you or
texts you that you can still see it and
actually, look at that. Oh, it
automatically answers on speaker. But
this is just not a very good way to be
handling your call. Can you hear me?
>> It's pretty clear. It's got that
standard underwater vibe.
>> Underwater vibe. So, even maybe while my
phone's propped up there. Hello. Yeah,
in terms of clarity, I can hear you.
>> Okay. But it's still just a slightly
worse way of answering the call on the
front of your phone cuz there's no mic
at [music] the back here. So, this part
of the phone's functionality I'm not
really sold on, especially considering
that Xiaomi actually has their own
version of Dynamic Island for secondary
things like this. But the camera
experience, which does also involve this
rear screen, is oh my god. Okay, so the
cameras on this phone, I wouldn't call
them a breakthrough in themselves, but
they're really good. The photos it takes
[music] are actually pretty much always
as detailed as the iPhone 17 Pro Maxes,
if not sometimes more with also
incredible dynamic range. Though, it
does do something very strange with my
skin tone that even if I disable every
beauty setting, I cannot get rid of. But
my suspicion is that's because this
model currently being China only means
that they've tuned it to Chinese
preferences. The ultrawide camera is
this tiny little reject at the bottom.
And it's kind of like you'd expect, not
particularly good in low light, but it
keeps up during the day. And the zoom is
really powerful. A little heavy-handed
on the AI image enhancement when you
zoom in a lot. But nonetheless, it's
hard to argue the results aren't
impressive. [music] Here's the thing,
though. When you've got a set of cameras
that are already really good compared to
other 2025 phones as rear cameras, then
that is going to completely obliterate
other phones when you compare it to
their front cameras. I mean, look how
three-dimensional and depthy the Xiaomi
shot looks here compared to the iPhone's
brand new revised front camera. And the
way that the second screen is
implemented here is awesome. Because if
I'm using the camera on my front screen
and I want to turn it around, all I have
to do is to turn it around and swipe.
And then when the camera is active on
this rear screen, the front screen
switches to now needing a swipe, which
straight away almost completely
eliminates the accidental presses
problem. But the other thing that's
really impressive about this is when
you're using this back screen, you
basically retain complete camera
functionality. So I can take normal
photos, which look crazy good. I can go
to all my different zoom magnifications.
So 2x, I can go to 5x for if you want to
capture an absolutely harrowing amount
of detail in your face. I'm actually so
sorry for showing this to you. You can
use the ultra wide camera, which is
actually a tiny bit wider than the
widest setting on the new iPhone's front
camera. Plus also, you've got portrait
mode. You can take video and you can
take that video in any quality. So, I've
been shooting selfie video in 8K [music]
resolution. And yeah, it does look a
little oversharpened, but there is
absolutely zero doubt in my mind that
this is the highest quality selfie video
I have ever taken. And it's all finished
off with this photo collage mode, which
is so thoughtfully designed. You take a
few photos back to back and it puts them
together into a Polaroid. Very much like
a photo booth that then lets you hit one
button over here to actually print.
[music] I'm just so takenback by the
amount of effort that's gone into custom
graphics and animations for this one
tiny feature on this one tiny [music]
second screen. Now, this isn't flawless.
I wouldn't say that this is a completely
intuitive gesture that you're going to
want to do 15 times a day. And if you
think about it, modernday flip phones
can do the same thing with their Bria
cameras on the front, but straight away
the moment you take them out your
pocket. But then none of them have
cameras this good. I will say the camera
experience here is such a big perk that
it straight away on its own takes me to
quite close to the fence. And then the
strangest cherry on top ever, you can
even game on this [music] second screen.
Xiaomi have actually gone as far as to
create a completely bespoke case that is
a working controller for the phone that
is wirelessly powered by the phone to be
able to game on this sub 3in display.
So, the case clips onto the back of
here. When you hold this power button,
it turns on and the back screen
recognizes it immediately. And then it's
got this entirely bespoke gaming
interface.
Why does it look so good? So, let's just
load up Angry Birds. And even the
controls feel really good for buttons
that have like a 2 mm travel distance.
They've even built bespoke tutorials
designed around the buttons Xiaomi's
using here. It's such a strange little
gaming experience. It's this tiny little
screen, but the game looks and runs
fantastic. I'm so in awe while also
knowing that I will never ever actually
play like this. So, on balance, I'm
nearly convinced by this back screen,
but not quite. I think the camera stuff
is majorly useful. I think the music
control and the sheer level of
personalization is so cool, but most of
the rest of the stuff does feel like
filler, and this gaming case is like the
definition of let's do something crazy
because it will make for great headlines
and [music] YouTube shorts. But this
whole thing has successfully drawn my
attention to the phone. And now my
attention is on the phone. I like what I
see.